Mikayla Timm

Website: mtimm100.github.io | Email: mtimm100@gmail.com | Phone: 850-502-7787

SUMMARY

Experienced in solving problems in research and industry using machine learning, computer vision, and natural language processing on large scale datasets. Proficient with PyTorch, Python, Java, C, Git, and UNIX. Two computer vision publications and presentations in CVPR workshops and two applied ML publications. Activist for diversity in computing. Delivered research prototypes and ML/computer vision software systems working both independently and on a team.

EDUCATION

University of Massachusetts Amherst M.S. in Computer Science | GPA: 3.968

SEPT 2017 - JAN 2020 Amherst, MA

University of West Florida

AUG 2014 - MAY 2017

B.S. in Computer Science, Math Minor | GPA: 3.99

Pensacola, FL

EXPERIENCE

Systems and Technology Research, *Machine Learning Researcher*

JAN 2020 - PRESENT

- Developed and integrated multi-target vehicle tracker and multi-task deep visual feature extractor into production pipeline for re-identifying vehicles in traffic camera videos, estimating proximity of cameras in traffic camera networks, and modeling traffic activity over time.
- Synthesized traffic camera video data at scale using Unity game engine perception tools.
- Trained robust deep reinforcement learning agents in Unity wargame environments using graph-based representations. Improved training speed and performance by optimizing game state representations and reducing message-passing overhead.

University of Massachusetts Amherst, Graduate Research Assistant

SEPT 2017 - JAN 2020

- Trained deep learning models for classifying attributes of textures, generating natural language descriptions of texture images, and image retrieval from natural language.
- Collected two novel vision and language datasets using Amazon Mechanical Turk.
- Developed end-to-end pipeline for labeling, training, and classifying animal species in camera trap images for ecology researchers.

Pinterest, Inc., Machine Learning Research Intern

MAY 2019 - AUG 2019

- Trained and evaluated new and existing computer vision models for fashion image retrieval and recommendation systems using image embeddings conditioned on specific attributes (color, pattern, fabric).
- Implemented and deployed data pipeline for processing and visualizing new fashion datasets.
- Utilized AWS EC2 P3 instances to efficiently train distributed deep models in the cloud.

MIT Lincoln Laboratory, NLP Summer Research Intern

JUNE 2017 - AUG 2017

- Researched NLP techniques to generate word embeddings on inherently multilingual data.
- Designed a pipeline for preprocessing multilingual text corpora, training new embeddings, performing intrinsic evaluations, and visualizing embeddings with dimensionality reduction.

University of West Florida, Undergraduate Research Scholar

MAY 2016 - MAY 2017

- Applied ML to classify biometric data from simulated wearable device cyber attacks.
- Implemented supervised learning algorithms to predict outcomes of animals in shelters.

University of Massachusetts Amherst, NSF REU Summer Researcher

MAY 2015 - AUG 2015

• Automated the identification of individual jaguars in images using computer vision.

HONORS AND AWARDS

NSF GRFP Honorable Mention. CVPR Women in Computer Vision Research Travel Grant. CRA-W Grad Cohort Workshop Award. UMass CICS Edward Riseman and Allen Hanson Scholarship. Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing Scholar. UWF Outstanding Undergraduate Student in Comp Sci. UWF Best Student Research Project in Comp Sci. 1st Place in ACM ICPC Southeast Division 2.